<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jonathon Lacher</title>
    <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jonathon Lacher</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 07:51:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jonathonlacher.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my Mac</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2025-05-19-setting-up-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 07:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2025-05-19-setting-up-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;mac-settings&#34;&gt;Mac Settings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A post about how I set up my Mac.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ll likely make minor updates as things change.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However if I radically change how I do this, I&amp;rsquo;ll make a new post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;enable-time-machine&#34;&gt;Enable Time Machine&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have at Synology NAS, which makes the backups easy.&#xA;I highly recommend using Time Machine for backups, even to a external drive.&#xA;It not only makes it easy to backup / restore files, but you can essentially restore your entire system to a previous state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linking to Apple Notes from another note</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2025-4-28-link-apple-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 22:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2025-4-28-link-apple-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To quickly add a link to another note, type &amp;raquo; to have a list of your notes appear. Begin typing to narrow your results, then select the note you want to link to. When you use this shortcut, the link title always matches the current title of the linked note.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/guide/notes/add-links-apde615d29c2/mac&#34;&gt;Add links in Notes on Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was making a checklist note that was a checklist of other notes, and thought there must be a way to link to a note.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mill glaze</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2025-02-12-mill-glaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 22:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2025-02-12-mill-glaze/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I built a wood fence this past summer, and the stain I used made a big deal about mill glaze.&#xA;This was a new term for me, so I had to look it up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It seems to be something that stain manufacturers and many online sources talk about, but there&amp;rsquo;s little evidence based research about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the mid-1980s, a condition called “mill glaze” (also called planer’s glaze) has sometimes been blamed for the failure of a coating on smooth flat-grained siding and some other wood products. The exact cause of this problem has been a subject of controversy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planes Overhead</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2024-11-17-planes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 11:26:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2024-11-17-planes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For seeing what planes are overhead, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://globe.adsbexchange.com/&#34;&gt;ADS-B Exchange&lt;/a&gt; since its a free-er version of the more commercial apps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However in writing this, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that they&amp;rsquo;ve also &lt;a href=&#34;https://old.reddit.com/r/ADSB/comments/10utxvi/hey_there_just_joined_because_i_noticed_that/&#34;&gt;sold out&lt;/a&gt;, and many folks have even moved on from it.&#xA;According to the thread &lt;a href=&#34;https://globe.adsb.fi/&#34;&gt;globe.adsb.fi&lt;/a&gt; now seems to have community support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOD Contracts</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2024-11-17-dod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 07:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2024-11-17-dod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apparently most (all?) new DOD contracts are posted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.defense.gov/News/Contracts/&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinesis update</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2023-10-25-kinesis-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 03:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2023-10-25-kinesis-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s much more difficult to learn a new keyboard that I thought.&#xA;The multi-key shortcuts are the hardest to re-learn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 trying the Kinesis Advantage 2</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2023-07-27-kinesis-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 13:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2023-07-27-kinesis-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why am I trying an ergo keyboard?&#xA;Was starting to feel some mild hand pain, and I&amp;rsquo;ve never bought my own keyboard before, so this seemed like a good excuse to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing-my-typing&#34;&gt;Testing my typing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To gauge my typing abilities, I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://typetest.io/&#34;&gt;TypeTest.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll use a 1 minute test, simple word list, punctuation and numbers off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-typing-speed&#34;&gt;Current typing speed&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My daily driver keyboard is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MQ052LL/A/magic-keyboard-with-numeric-keypad-us-english&#34;&gt;Apple Magic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On TypeTest.io, I&amp;rsquo;m around 64 words per minute.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 04:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book notes: A Philosophy of Software Design, Chapters 1-3</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2022-01-18-software-design-book-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 03:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2022-01-18-software-design-book-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a series of posts of my notes on the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.stanford.edu/~ouster/cgi-bin/book.php&#34;&gt;A Philosophy of Software Design&lt;/a&gt; by John Ousterhout.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of my notes are loosely copied quotes, paraphrases, or summaries of my understanding.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve included the page number (from my edition) in parentheses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The greatest limitation in writing software is our ability to understand the systems we are creating. (1)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are two approaches to fighting complexity.&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eliminate complexity by making code simpler and more obvious. (2)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Encapsulate it, so you can work on the system without being exposed to all the complexity at once (2)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Book as two goals: (3)&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Describe the nature of software complexity, what does &amp;ldquo;complexity&amp;rdquo; mean, why does it matter, how can you recognize it?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Present techniques you can use to help minimize complexity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Best way to use this book is in conjunction with code reviews. (4)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Good way to improve design skills to to learn go recognize red flags (4)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moderation and discretion is important. Everything has limits, don&amp;rsquo;t take the ideas in this book to the extreme. (4)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Complexity is anything related to the structure of a software system that makes it hard to understand and modify. (5)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Complexity is more apparent to readers than writers. (6)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Symptoms of complexity:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change amplification: A seemingly simple change requires modifications in many places. (7)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cognitive load: An engineer needs to spend a lot more time learning and needs to hold much more info in their mind to make the change. Complexity isn&amp;rsquo;t measured in the number of lines; sometimes the more verbose version of code is simpler because it&amp;rsquo;s not trying to be clever. (7)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unknown unknowns: When it&amp;rsquo;s not obvious what pieces of code must be modified to complete a task or even what info is needed to complete the task. This is the worst symptom, since you only find out about it after something unknown rears its head. (9)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Causes of complexity:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dependencies&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A dep exists when a piece of code can&amp;rsquo;t be understood and modified in isolation. (9)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Deps can&amp;rsquo;t be eliminated, but we can be intentional.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Two goals of software design: (10) 1. Reduce the number of deps 2. Make deps that remain simple and obvious&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Obscurity&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Occurs when important information is not obvious.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Obscurity is often associated with deps, where it&amp;rsquo;s not obvious that a dep exists. (10)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Inconsistency is also a major contributor to obscurity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The need for extensive docs is often a red flag that the design isn&amp;rsquo;t good.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Complexity isn&amp;rsquo;t caused by a single terrible error, but accumulates in small chunks over time. (11)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once complexity has accumulated, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to eliminate since fixing any one issue won&amp;rsquo;t make a big difference. (11)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In order to slow the growth of complexity, we must have a zero tolerance approach.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3&#34;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tactical programming is the mindset of only getting something working, nothing else is considered. (13)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The problem with tactical programming is it&amp;rsquo;s short sighted. The accumulation of just trying to introduce a new feature or fix a bug introduces complexity and kludges, which is how systems get complicated. (13)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once you start taking the tactical approach, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to change. (14)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tactical tornado: A prolific programmer who pumps out code faster than others but in a totally tactical fashion. They may be admired by management, but they leave a wake of destruction and messes that other engineers must clean up. (14)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strategic programming: Working code isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. The most important thing is the long-term structure of the system. Your primary goal is to produce a great design which also happens to work. (14)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strategic programming requires an investment mindset. Rather than taking the shortest and fastest path to finishing something, you must invest time to improve the design of the system. (15)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Continually make small improvements to system design: (15)&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Iterate on a design, don&amp;rsquo;t use the first one you think of.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Imagine a few ways a system might need to be changed in the future and make sure the current design makes this easy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write good documentation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Big upfront investments in design don&amp;rsquo;t work, this is waterfall. The best approach is lots of small investments on a continual basis. (15)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Suggestion: spend 10%-20% of total development time on investments. While you make take 10-20% longer at first, these will pay off in the long-run and future changes will be easier. (15-16)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once a codebase is spaghetti, it&amp;rsquo;s nearly impossible to fix. (17)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The most important factor of success in a company is the quality of its engineers. The best engineers care deeply about good design. (17)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once you start delaying design improvements, it&amp;rsquo;s easy for delays to become permanent and your culture will slip into the tactical approach. (18)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter heating</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-11-20-heating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 06:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-11-20-heating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We bought a house, it was built in the 1920s and the main floor uses hot water radiators as the primary heat source (boiler is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.weil-mclain.com/sites/default/files/field-file/cgm-pcg-series-4-manual_1.pdf&#34;&gt;Weil-McLain CG-4&lt;/a&gt;). I also have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://nonul.mylinkdrive.com/item/MXZ-3A30NA-1.html&#34;&gt;three zone Mitsubishi mini-split system&lt;/a&gt;, with two zones upstairs and one on the main floor. The upstairs also has electric baseboard heat in all rooms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding which sources of heat to use this winter is a challenge. The mini-split can be an effective heat source compared to electric baseboard heat, but the efficiency depends on the outside temp and how much heat each indoor unit is requesting. My understanding is that mini-splits are most efficient when running on low. This means setting large setbacks temps at night could actually end up using more electricity than keeping the temp constant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network debugging with MTR</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-8-3-mtr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 02:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-8-3-mtr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been dealing with intermittent packet loss at my current home connection. I initially wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if the issue was with my home router/switch or my ISP. With MTR, I found the issue wasn&amp;rsquo;t with my home equipment, but somewhere after my ISP&amp;rsquo;s router.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/traviscross/mtr&#34;&gt;MTR&lt;/a&gt; has been around for a few decades now, but I discovered it in the past few years. It&amp;rsquo;s a mashup of traceroute and ping and is useful for diagnosing network issues and quality. It essentially shows each hop between you and the endpoint, with packet loss percentage and ping information to each hop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I don&#39;t listen to white noise (An ode to brown noise)</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-7-23-brown-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 13:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-7-23-brown-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I need to focus in a distracting or noisy environment, I use a combination of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bose.com/en_us/support/products/bose_headphones_support/bose_around_ear_headphones_support/quietcomfort-25-acoustic-noise-cancelling-headphones-apple-devices.html&#34;&gt;noise canceling headphones&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brownian_noise&#34;&gt;brownian (brown) noise&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I find music and spoken word to be mostly distracting, but not listening to anything with noise canceling headphones doesn&amp;rsquo;t work so well.&#xA;The combination of a wall of random frequencies and the noise canceling does a great job of blocking and masking outside noises.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why not white noise?&#xA;I find the frequencies too harsh; brown noise is more soothing, like an ocean wave.&#xA;My current favorite noise generator is &lt;a href=&#34;https://playnoise.com/&#34;&gt;playnoise.com&lt;/a&gt; which has white, grey, pink, and brown, plus an option to enable the noises in stereo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where I get my weather forecasts</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-7-15-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 02:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-7-15-weather/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been an Android user for the last 10 years, and for the last 3-4 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://darksky.net/&#34;&gt;Dark Sky&lt;/a&gt; weather app.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However they recently announce they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.darksky.net/dark-sky-has-a-new-home/&#34;&gt;shutting down the Android app&lt;/a&gt;, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been researching which weather services will fit my needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For near-term weather (the next 12-120 hours) I use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forecast.weather.gov/&#34;&gt;National Weather Service&lt;/a&gt;, I especially like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forecast.weather.gov/product.php?site=MPX&amp;amp;issuedby=MPX&amp;amp;product=AFD&amp;amp;format=CI&amp;amp;version=1&amp;amp;glossary=1&#34;&gt;Area Forecast Discussion&lt;/a&gt; which is written a human, and gives insight and more color into the weather than just reading a 5 day forecast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flickr&#39;s Camera Finder</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-7-5-flickr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 02:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-7-5-flickr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a temptation in photography to ascribe gear like an expensive camera body or a fast n&amp;rsquo; sharp lens as the the reason great photos are great.&#xA;As if the gear itself will propel my photos from &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One resource I&amp;rsquo;ve found as a &amp;ldquo;check&amp;rdquo; against gear creep is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/cameras&#34;&gt;Flickr&amp;rsquo;s Camera Finder&lt;/a&gt;. With this tool, I can filter photos by camera body.&#xA;As an example I have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/cameras/olympus/e-m10markii/&#34;&gt;Olympus&amp;rsquo;s EM10 Mark II&lt;/a&gt;, so I can find all the photos on Flickr taken with this body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts I like</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-6-26-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 03:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-6-26-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pocketcasts.com/&#34;&gt;Pocket Casts&lt;/a&gt; (my preferred podcast player) says I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to 1038 hours of audio since 2015.&#xA;This sounds like a lot, but per week it&amp;rsquo;s only &lt;code&gt;1038 / 5 / 52&lt;/code&gt; ~ 4 hours.&#xA;But it&amp;rsquo;s the consistency that counts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll detail the podcasts I love and why.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-podcasts&#34;&gt;The podcasts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://conversationswithtyler.com/&#34;&gt;Conversations with Tyler&lt;/a&gt; by far is the most engaging and stimulating for me.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s a discussion format show, where Tyler interviews different notable individuals each episode.&#xA;I value thoughtful and engaging questions in interviews, and Tyler provides.&#xA;I only discovered the show in the last 6 months, and I&amp;rsquo;m catching up. The format is economist Tyler Cowen interviews a wide variety of intellectuals covering a wide range of topics.&#xA;Tyler specializes in pointed and rapid fire questions, it is clear he spends much time preparing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac window wrangling</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-6-25-rectangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 03:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-6-25-rectangle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that my experience with macOS/OSX only goes back a few years, but I was instantly frustrated with window management.&#xA;Most folks around me seemed to have a sea of small windows that would pile up over the course of a day, maybe they would use mission control to switch between windows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But for tasks where two windows were needed at the same time (for example side by side), most folks were content enough to simply drag and resize windows into place.&#xA;This seemed insane.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FCC broadband map</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-6-24-fcc-fiber/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 02:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-6-24-fcc-fiber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m looking at property, one of the additional research steps I take is figuring out the available internet providers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initially I would Google something like &amp;ldquo;internet options at address&amp;rdquo; and some site like &lt;em&gt;highspeedinternet.com&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;broadbandnow.com&lt;/em&gt; would pop up.&#xA;These sites are &lt;em&gt;fine&lt;/em&gt;, but have ads and are definitely funnels to get you to sign up for something.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://broadbandmap.fcc.gov/&#34;&gt;broadbandmap.fcc.gov&lt;/a&gt;, which gives per census block internet provider data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I manage my Lightroom library</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-27-lightroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 13:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-27-lightroom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After I bought a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getolympus.com/us/en/e-m10-mark-ii.html&#34;&gt;mirrorless micro four thirds camera&lt;/a&gt; last year, I&amp;rsquo;ve entered the rabbit whole of media management.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started by shooting in JPEG and dumping the images I liked into Google Photos, simple enough, right?&#xA;After a while, for various reasons, I started shooting in RAW.&#xA;But after filling my first SD card full of RAW files, I realized I needed a way to process them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lightroom seems to be the default choice, so I went with that.&#xA;I know there are open source alternatives like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.darktable.org/&#34;&gt;Darktable&lt;/a&gt;, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t invested much time into exploring it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Memphis</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-24-corperate-memphis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-24-corperate-memphis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a &lt;a href=&#34;https://todoist.com/&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt; user, you may have seen this image&#xA;&lt;picture&gt;&#xA;    &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-24-corperate-memphis/todoist_hu_81511651c131b379.webp&#34; type=&#34;image/webp&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-24-corperate-memphis/todoist_hu_9225ee7a93ab7dad.jpg&#34; type=&#34;image/jpeg&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-24-corperate-memphis/todoist_hu_d0d45a4d84adaa0a.jpg&#34; &#xA;         alt=&#34;Todoist app interface showing Corporate Memphis style illustration&#34;&#xA;         loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&#xA;         width=&#34;600&#34;&#xA;         height=&#34;489&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/picture&gt;&#xA;Even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t, the style may look familiar.&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.are.na/claire-l-evans/corporate-memphis&#34;&gt;100s (1000s?) of organizations use the same style&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/quartzy/1728767/why-editorial-illustrations-look-so-similar-these-days/&#34;&gt;Quartz article&lt;/a&gt; elaborates more on the trend:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s most widely referred to as “flat illustration” or, pejoratively, “Corporate Memphis,” alluding to its frequent appearance in ads and interfaces for tech companies like Lyft, Spotify, Oscar, Airtable, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Craigslist search operators</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-19-craigslist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-19-craigslist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently searching for a second vehicle and have been trolling Craigslist postings.&#xA;I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.craigslist.org/about/saved_searches_and_alerts&#34;&gt;saved searches&lt;/a&gt; set up, but was receiving a lot of false positives because nothing stops unrelated postings from keyword stuffing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I found that Craigslist has surprising robust &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.craigslist.org/about/help/search&#34;&gt;search operators&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, I used this search:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34; data-lang=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;hybrid -truck -.com -ford -buick -dodge -chrysler -hyundai -lincoln -kia -cadillac&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a &lt;code&gt;hybrid&lt;/code&gt;, and don&amp;rsquo;t want any post with &lt;code&gt;truck&lt;/code&gt; or various manufacturers or &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt; (which is typically a dealer, I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a private seller).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sync your laptop and external monitor brightness</title>
      <link>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-16-lunar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 23:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jonathonlacher.com/posts/2020-5-16-lunar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since working from home, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using an external monitor more heavily.&#xA;The light in my office changes throughout the day, and I found myself adjusting the brightness on my MacBook and external monitor separately.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started looking for a utility that would link the brightness of the MBP and my external monitor, and I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://lunar.fyi/&#34;&gt;Lunar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In sync mode, the brightness of the laptop and external monitor are linked, which means I only need to adjust one brightness level for both.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
